# MARCO MARCHIONNI

JAVA FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

+39 349 877 23 07

marco.marchionni@gmail.com

marcomarchionni.com

in linkedin.com/in/ marcomarchionni

github.com/ marcomarchionni

via Posillipo 406, 80123 Napoli, Italy

#### SKILLS

#### Languages

Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, DAX

#### Frontend

HTML, CSS, SCSS, jQuery, React, React Native, Angular, Bootstrap, Angular Material

#### **Backend**

Node.js, Express, Spring, Spring Boot, MongoDB, MySQL, Swagger

#### Cloud

AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda, Elastic Beanstalk), Heroku, MongoDbAtlas

#### **Tools**

Git, Maven, Parcel, VSCode, Intellij Idea, Github Copilot

## **EDUCATION**

Cloud Computing for Web Developers CareerFoundry (2023)

Full-Stack Development Program CareerFoundry (2023)

Filmmaking Intensive **New York University** 

Laurea cum laude: Lettere Moderne **University of Bologna** 

#### PROFILE

Full-stack developer focused on Java/Spring, React and Angular, with a diverse skill set in other programming languages and frameworks (Node.js, .NET, DAX) and the ability to swiftly learn and adapt to new technologies.

Developed a unique blend of creativity, technical expertise, and disciplined thinking through key roles in the film/TV industry and in stock and option trading.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT

## **Full-Stack Developer**

<u>Insurance Broker Assistance</u> - Jellyfish Tech.

2024

- Developed a user-friendly frontend using React for an insurance management application, enhancing the broker's ability to track customer interactions and product details.
- Integrated .NET Core APIs to handle data transactions, including querying and managing customer and product information from multiple insurance companies.

## Java Full-Stack Developer

PortfolioStrategist - Personal Project

2022-2024

- Developed a backend with Spring Boot to retrieve and manage trading data from Interactive Brokers web server.
- Engineered a responsive Angular frontend with Syncfusion components for enhanced data guerying and manipulation.
- Deployed test version on AWS laying the groundwork for a potential startup.

## **Full-Stack Developer**

Flixit - CareerFoundry (Educational Project)

2023

- Constructed a REST API with Node.js and Express to enable user registration and movie information queries.
- Developed two frontend variations (React and Angular) for user login, movie information display, and favorite list creation.

## OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Stock and Option Trader**

Self-employed

2013-2024

- Pursued long and short-term investment goals using planning, analitycal and organizational skills.
- Utilized Motley Fool principles for option trading, employing advanced strategies such as bull put/calls, diagonal calls, covered calls, etc.
- Built software tools with Google App Script for insight and data analysis.

#### **TV Producer and Scriptwriter**

Mediaset, Rai, Publispei and others

2001-2012, 2019-2021

- Successfully managed large TV projects through effective team management and leadership
- Produced multiple popular shows for Mediaset, a major Italian TV Network (L'onore e il rispetto, I Cesaroni, Rivombrosa)
- Authored award-winning scripts for films and TV series.